Guide to the Margaret S. Mahler Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Foundation Materials, 1939-1985; Series IX; 5; (12 boxes)
  - General, 1939-1985
    - Correspondence and Subject Files
      - Paul, Viola, 1972 (Box 184, Folder 2551)
      - Pavenstedt, Eleanor, M.D, 1971 (Box 184, Folder 2552)
      - Perry, Irma P., 1976 (Box 184, Folder 2553)
      - Rabinovitch, Ruth, M.D, 1966 (Box 184, Folder 2554)
      - Reiss, Annaliese, 1970 (Box 184, Folder 2555)
      - Robsahm, Claire, 1959, 1966-1970 (Box 184, Folder 2556)
      - Robsahm, Eva, 1971 (Box 184, Folder 2557)
      - Rohricht, Heidi, 1974–1975 (Box 184, Folder 2558)
      - Root, Diana, 1970 (Box 184, Folder 2559)
      - Samet, Bernhard, 1949, 1961, 1972-1973 (Box 184, Folder 2560)
      - Sandler, Joseph, 1974, 1975, 1979 (Box 184, Folder 2561)
      - Satinski, Victor P., 1954, undated (Box 184, Folder 2562)
      - Schmidt, Edith Taglicht (ted), 1955, 1967, 1970-1972, 1975 (Box 184, Folder 2563)
      - Schoenberger, Susanna, 1947–1949 (Box 184, Folder 2564)
      - Schoenberger, Susanna, 1950–1952 (Box 184, Folder 2565)
      - Schoenberger, Susanna, 1965–1970 (Box 184, Folder 2566)
      - Schoenberger, Susanna, 1947–1959 (Box 184, Folder 2567)
      - Schoenberger, Susanna, 1960–1970 (Box 184, Folder 2568)
      - Schoenberger, Susanna (fragments), undated (Box 184, Folder 2569)
      - Schwarz, Eugen, 1946-1947, 1951 (Box 185, Folder 2570)
      - Schwarz, Peter, 1957 (Box 185, Folder 2571)
      - Sciaky, Leon & Frances, 1958 (Box 185, Folder 2572)
      - Science Magazine, 1970 (Box 185, Folder 2573)
      - Secretaries, 1967, 1974, 1976 (Box 185, Folder 2574)
      - Settlage, Calvin F., M.D, 1968, 1970, 1971, 1974 (Box 185, Folder 2575)
      - Shalsha, L., 194?, 1974 (Box 185, Folder 2576)
      - Shanzer, Hilda, 1971 (Box 185, Folder 2577)
      - Socarides, Charles, 1970 (Box 185, Folder 2578)
      - Solnit, Albert J., 1971 (Box 185, Folder 2579)
      - Solims, Wilhelm, 1970 (Box 185, Folder 2580)
      - Stiefel, Rudy C., 1969 (Box 185, Folder 2581)
      - Stark, Mort, 1968 (Box 185, Folder 2582)
      - Stransky, Hilda, 1971–1973 (Box 185, Folder 2583)
      - Sulczer, George & Lili, undated (Box 185, Folder 2584)
      - Sweeney, Mary, 1969, undated (Box 185, Folder 2585)
      - Takacs, Jëno, 1949 (Box 185, Folder 2586)
      - Tumarian, Bertha, 1969 (Box 185, Folder 2587)
      - Vertes, Katarina, 1972 (Box 185, Folder 2588)
      - Wallace, Harry & Joan, 1972 (Box 185, Folder 2589)
      - Walsh, Marna, 1965 (Box 185, Folder 2590)
      - Wangh, Martin, 1985 (Box 185, Folder 2591)
      - Weller, Hildegard, 1972 (Box 185, Folder 2592)
      - West Village Nursery School, 1965 (Box 185, Folder 2593)
      - Willey, Iris, 1984 (Box 185, Folder 2594)
      - Williams, Miriam, 1969 (Box 185, Folder 2595)
      - Windholz, ?, 1966 (Box 185, Folder 2596)
      - Unidentified, undated (Box 185, Folder 2597)
      - Unidentified, 1949-1942, 1947, 1951, 1966-1968, 1970, 1973, 1974 (Box 185, Folder 2598)
    - Professional Associations
      - New York Psychoanalytic Institute Budgetary Matters, 1972 (Box 185, Box 2599)
      - New York Psychoanalytic Institute Committees Nominating Committee, 1973 (Box 185, Folder 2600)
      - New York Psychoanalytic Institute Committees Program Committee, 1972 (Box 185, Folder 2601)
      - New York Institute Correspondence Furer-Ennis, 1972 (Box 185, Folder 2602)
      - Project=Film "Iris: The longitudinal study of the treatments of a psychotic child with the tripartite design" Sketchbook, undated (Box 185, Folder 2603)
    - Correspondence
      - Study Families, 1983 (Box 185, Folder 2604)
    - Photographs
      - Study Children (Amy & Alex Colt, Linda, Mathew, Various Identified), undated (Box 185, Folder 2605)
      - Study Children (Jaffe, Deborah), 1970 (Box 185, Folder 2606)
  - Margaret S. Mahler Psychiatric Research Fund, 1963-1985
    - Administrative
      - Board of Advisors
        - Aims and Purposes, 1972 (Box 140, Folder 2036)
        - Agreement, 1971–1972 (Box 140, Folder 2037)
        - Addendum to Agreement, 1976 (Box 140, Folder 2038)
        - Annual Report, 1975 (Box 140, Folder 2039)
        - Certificate of Incorporation, 1976 (Box 140, Folder 2040)
        - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 140, Folder 2041)
        - Minutes, 1972–1976 (Box 140, Folder 2042)
        - Officers, 1976 (Box 140, Folder 2043)
    - Committees
      - Archives Committee
        - General Information, 1972–1973 (Box 140, Folder 2044)
        - Guidelines, 1972–1973 (Box 140, Folder 2045)
        - Lubeck, Paul, 1973–1975 (Box 140, Folder 2046)
        - Microfilm, Microfiche, 1973 (Box 140, Folder 2047)
        - Minutes, 1973 (Box 140, Folder 2048)
        - Roberts, Gloria, 1973 (Box 140, Folder 2049)
        - Salchow, Laura, 1973–1978 (Box 140, Folder 2050)
        - Van Vlack, Jacques D., 1973–1975 (Box 140, Folder 2051)
      - Executive Committee, 1972–1976 (Box 140, Folder 2052)
      - Fundraising, 1975 (Box 140, Folder 2053)
      - Grant Committee, 1974 (Box 140, Folder 2054)
      - Hurwich Project, 1974 (Box 140, Folder 2055)
      - Mahler Festschrift, 1968–1971 (Box 140, Folder 2056)
      - Literature Prize, 1974–1976 (Box 140, Folder 2057)
      - Literature Prize, 1980, undated (Box 140, Folder 2058)
      - Planning Committee, 1972 (Box 141, Folder 2059)
      - Member Lists, undated (Box 141, Folder 2060)
      - Publications, 1972 (Box 141, Folder 2061)
    - Equipment Inventory, 1977 (Box 141, Folder 2062)
    - Organizational Chart, undated (Box 141, Folder 2063)
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1972–1977 (Box 141, Folder 2064)
      - Apfel, Jerome B., esq. Blank, Rome, Klaus and Komisky, 1972–1977 (Box 141, Folder 2065)
      - Board Members, 1973–1977 (Box 141, Folder 2066)
      - Fishman, Bernard D. Shea, Gould, Climenko and Casey, 1976–1978 (Box 141, Folder 2067)
      - Kramer, Selma, 1972-1977, undated (Box 141, Folder 2068)
      - Lipton, Edgar, 1976–1977 (Box 141, Folder 2069)
      - McDevitt, John, 1972-1977, undated (Box 141, Folder 2070)
      - Mahler, Margaret, 1972–1973 (Box 141, Folder 2071)
      - de Menil, Adelaide, 1972–1976 (Box 141, Folder 2072)
      - de Menil, Dominique, 1973–1979 (Box 141, Folder 2073)
      - de Menil, George and Louis, 1974–1975 (Box 141, Folder 2074)
      - de Menil, Christophe, Francois, and Jean, 1973, undated (Box 141, Folder 2075)
      - de Menil Foundation, 1972 (Box 141, Folder 2076)
      - Pacella, Bernard L., 1973–1976 (Box 141, Folder 2077)
      - Parens, Henri, 1972–1976 (Box 141, Folder 2078)
      - Prall, Robert, 1972-1977, undated (Box 141, Folder 2079-2080)
      - Sculpture, 1972–1973 (Box 141, Folder 2081)
      - Stark, Morton, 1973 (Box 141, Folder 2082)
      - Sternschein, Irving, 1976–1977 (Box 141, Folder 2083)
    - Financial
      - Accounting Procedures, 1972 (Box 141, Folder 2084)
      - Annual Reports, 1973–1976 (Box 141, Folder 2085)
      - Budget, 1973–1978 (Box 141, Folder 2086)
      - Contribution lists, 1972–1977 (Box 142, Folder 2087)
      - Correspondence
        - Blazek, Jody, 1972–1974 (Box 142, Folder 2088)
        - Contributions, 1972-1977, undated (Box 142, Folder 2089)
        - Kramer, Selma, 1972–1979 (Box 142, Folder 2090)
        - Mahler, Margaret, 1972–1977 (Box 142, Folder 2091)
        - de Menil Foundation, 1972-1976, undated (Box 142, Folder 2092)
        - Prall, Robert, 1972–1978 (Box 142, Folder 2093)
        - Fundraising films, 1974–1976 (Box 142, Folder 2094)
        - Prospective donors, 1972, undated (Box 142, Folder 2095)
        - Disbursements/expenditures, 1976 (Box 142, Folder 2096)
        - Treasurer's reports, 1972–1977 (Box 142, Folder 2097)
        - Treasurer's reports, 1972–1977 (Box 142, Folder 2098)
    - Administrative
      - Aims and Purposes, undated (Box 142, Folder 2099)
      - Annual Report, 1979-1980, undated (Box 142, Folder 2100)
      - Articles of Incorporation, 1976 (Box 142, Folder 2101)
      - Amendments to Articles of Incorporation, 1977 (Box 142, Folder 2102)
      - By-laws, 1977–1983 (Box 142, Folder 2103)
      - Committees
        - Roster of Committee members, 1977-1985, undated (Box 142, Folder 2104)
        - Archives Committee
          - Correspondence
            - Anthony, James E., 1979 (Box 143, Folder 2105)
            - Baker, Doris, 1979 (Box 143, Folder 2106)
            - Child Development Film Archives-University of Akron, Ohio, 1976–1979 (Box 143, Folder 2107)
            - Fischman, Bernard, esq., 1979–1980 (Box 143, Folder 2108)
            - Levy, Darlene, 1978–1982 (Box 143, Folder 2109)
            - Mahler, Margaret, 1979–1982 (Box 143, Folder 2110)
            - New York Psychoanalytic Institute, 1983–1984 (Box 143, Folder 2111)
            - Winestine, Henry, 1979 (Box 143, Folder 2112)
            - Yale University, 1978–1985 (Box 143, Folder 2113-2114)
          - Donor Agreement-Yale, 1979–1980 (Box 143, Folder 2115-2116)
          - Film report, 1984, undated (Box 143, Folder 2117)
          - Information packet, 1979 (Box 143, Folder 2118)
          - Inventory of Margaret S. Mahler Research Fund, 1975 (Box 143, Folder 2119)
          - Empty (Box 143, Folder 2120-2122)
          - Empty (Box 144, Folder 2123-2124)
          - Film Inventory, 1980 (Box 144, Folder 2125)
          - Memoranda, 1978–1983 (Box 144, Folder 2126)
          - Minutes, 1978–1979 (Box 144, Folder 2127)
          - Reports, 1978 (Box 144, Folder 2128)
          - "Significance of Mahler Archives", 1978–1979 (Box 144, Folder 2129)
          - Work Files
            - Ann Fagan, 1978–1980 (Box 144, Folder 2130-2131)
            - Hermine Watterson, 1977–1984 (Box 144, Folder 2132)
        - Budget and Finance Committee
          - Minutes, 1978 (Box 144, Folder 2133)
        - Committee for Film Control, 1980 (Box 144, Folder 2134)
        - Fundraising Committee
          - General, 1978–1984 (Box 144, Folder 2135-2137)
          - Minutes, 1978–1981 (Box 144, Folder 2138)
          - Brochure Meetings, Brochures, 1978–1984 (Box 145, Folder 2139-2141)
        - Literature Prize Committee, 1976, 1983-1985, undated (Box 145, Folder 2142)
        - International Advisory Committee, 1983 (Box 145, Folder 2143)
        - Symposium Committee
          - Brochures, 1970–1985 (Box 145, Folder 2144)
          - Correspondence, 1976-1985, undated (Box 145, Folder 2145)
        - Ad Hoc Committee-The Bulletin of the New School of Social Research
          - Minutes, 1980 (Box 145, Folder 2146)
        - Ad Hoc Committee on International Separation-Individuation Conference
          - Correspondence, 1984–1985 (Box 145, Folder 2147)
          - Program, 1985 (Box 145, Folder 2148)
        - Ad Hoc Committee on Videotape and Film Projection, 1981–1982 (Box 145, Folder 2149)
      - Correspondence
        - Board Members, 1977–1978 (Box 145, Folder 2150)
        - General, 1976–1985 (Box 145, Folder 2151)
        - McDevitt, John, 1984, undated (Box 145, Folder 2152)
        - Pacella, Bernard L., 1978–1985 (Box 145, Folder 2153)
        - Sternschein, Irving, 1976–1985 (Box 145, Folder 2154)
      - Membership Rosters, 1976–1985 (Box 145, Folder 2155)
      - Officer Rosters, 1977–1983 (Box 145, Folder 2156)
      - Board of Trustees Rosters, 1977–1983 (Box 145, Folder 2157)
      - Minutes
        - General, 1976, 1980-1981, undated (Box 146, Folder 2158)
        - Annual Meeting, 1977–1984 (Box 146, Folder 2159-2161)
        - Board of Trustees, 1978-1985, undated (Box 146, Folder 2162)
        - Board of Trustees Executive Committee, 1976–1985 (Box 146, Folder 2163-2164)
    - Financial
      - Budgets, 1978–1985 (Box 146, Folder 2165)
      - Contribution Lists, 1972–1983 (Box 146, Folder 2166-2167)
      - Contribution Lists, 1984–1985 (Box 147, Folder 2168)
      - Correspondence
        - Blazek, Jody, 1978–1982 (Box 147, Folder 2169)
        - Contributions, 1978-1985, undated (Box 147, Folder 2170)
        - Department of the Treasury, Internal Revenue Service, 1976–1981 (Box 147, Folder 2171)
        - Gray Panthers Project Fund, 1983–1984 (Box 147, Folder 2172)
        - Lipton, Edgar, Treasurer, 1978–1982 (Box 147, Folder 2173)
        - de Menil, Dominique, 1978–1985 (Box 147, Folder 2174)
        - de Menil, George and Louis, 1980 (Box 147, Folder 2175)
        - Mahler, Margaret, 1979-1981, undated (Box 147, Folder 2176)
        - Prall, Robert, 1979 (Box 147, Folder 2177)
        - Shea, Gould, Climenko and Casey, 1977–1978 (Box 147, Folder 2178)
        - Sternschein, Irving, 1978-1985, undated (Box 147, Folder 2179)
      - Fundraising
        - General, 1977–1983 (Box 147, Folder 2180)
        - Films, 1980-1982, undated (Box 147, Folder 2181-2182)
        - Rock Foundation, Inc., 1976–1982 (Box 147, Folder 2183)
      - Tax Exemption annual reports and certificates, 1976–1981 (Box 147, Folder 2184)
      - Treasurer's Reports, 1977–1984 (Box 147, Folder 2185)
      - Treasurer's Reports Balance Sheets, 1980–1985 (Box 147, Folder 2186)
      - Treasurer's Records Stocks, 1976–1979 (Box 147, Folder 2187)
    - Projects
      - Mahler Teaching Fellowship and Observational Research Nursery
        - New School for Social Research, 1979–1985 (Box 147, Folder 2188-2190)
        - City College of the University of New York, 1980–1983 (Box 148, Folder 2191)
        - Sarah Lawrence College, 1984–1985 (Box 148, Folder 2192)
      - Pre-Nursery Program
        - Harvard Medical School-Beth Israel Hospital, 1975–1977 (Box 148, Folder 2193)
      - Lepzig-Dombro Dayare Project, 1984–1985 (Box 148, Folder 2194)
      - Iris Follow-up Study, 1980–1982 (Box 148, Folder 2195-2197)
      - Model Day Care Center, 1983–1984 (Box 148, Folder 2198)
      - The Mothers' Center, 1983–1984 (Box 148, Folder 2199-2200)
      - The Mothers' Center, 1983–1984 (Box 148, Folder 2201)
      - T. Berry Brazelton/Daniel Stern/Margaret s. Mahler Dialogue, 1980–1983 (Box 148, Folder 2202)
      - Films-"Edited Films"
        - List, 1975 (Box 148, Folder 2203)
        - Film Notes, 1966–1975 (Box 148, Folder 2204)
      - Film-"Highlights of the MotherChild Interaction"
        - Text, Film Notes, 1975 (Box 149, Folder 2205)
      - Film-"The Psychological Birth of the Human Infant", 1976 (Box 149, Folder 2206)
      - Film-"Iris-The Longitudinal Study of the Treatment of a Psychotic Child with the Tripartite Design"
        - Text, 1976 (Box 149, Folder 2207)
        - Puerto Rico Text, 1976 (Box 149, Folder 2208)
      - Film-"Basic Film-The Separation-Individuation Process: The Psychological Birth of the Human Infant"
        - Text, 1976-1983, undated (Box 149, Folder 2209-2215)
        - Notes, undated (Box 149, Folder 2215)
      - Film-"Separation-Individuation"
        - Text, 1977 (Box 150, Folder 2216)
        - Film Notes, 1963-1975, undated (Box 150, Folder 2217)
      - Film-"Hatching, Customs Inspection, and the Mirror Reaction"
        - Text, 1981 (Box 150, Folder 2218)
        - Proposal Notes, 1981 (Box 150, Folder 2219)
      - Film-"On Some Phenomena Indicative of the Emergence of the Self"
        - Text, 1982 (Box 150, Folder 2220)
        - Text, 1982 (Box 150, Folder 2221)
      - Film-"Condensed Version of the Basic Film"
        - Text, undated (Box 150, Folder 2222)
      - Film-"Mirror Reactions-Selected"
        - Film Notes, undated (Box 150, Folder 2223)
      - Film-General
        - Correspondence, 1964-1984, undated (Box 150, Folder 2224-2225)
        - Correspondence-Copyrights, 1979-1984, undated (Box 150, Folder 2226)
        - Equipment Inventory, 1983 (Box 151, Folder 2227)
        - Film Lists, 1977, undated (Box 151, Folder 2228)
        - Film List-Psychotic Children, undated (Box 151, Folder 2229)
        - Income, Distributions, 1980–1985 (Box 151, Folder 2230)
        - Preview Policy, 1984 (Box 151, Folder 2231)
        - Filming Schedule, 1964, undated (Box 151, Folder 2232)
        - Videotapes, 1982-1983, undated (Box 151, Folder 2233)
- Grant Files, 1955-1972; Series X; 2 linear feet (5 boxes)
  This series is arranged chronologically by project.
  - HEW, M-1307
    - Grant Application, 1956 (Box 152, Folder 2234)
    - Correspondence, 1955-1957 (Box 152, Folder 2235)
  - Field Foundation Study
    - Correspondence, 1958-1960 (Box 152, Folder 2236)
    - Application, 1959 (Box 152, Folder 2237)
    - Progress Reports, 1959 (Box 152, Folder 2238)
    - Notes, 1959-1961, undated (Box 152, Folder 2239)
  - Taconic Foundation Study
    - Correspondence and Application (Box 152, Folder 2240)
  - N.A.M.H.
    - Application, 1961 (Box 152, Folder 2241)
    - Correspondence, 1961-1963 (Box 152, Folder 2242)
    - News Release, 1962 Jan/February (Box 152, Folder 2243)
    - Progress Reports, 1962 (Box 152, Folder 2244)
    - Progress Reports and Drafts, 1962 (Box 152, Folder 2245)
    - Progress Reports and Final Drafts, 1963 (Box 152, Folder 2246)
  - Psychoanalytic Research and Development Fund
    - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 152, Folder 2247)
    - Application, 1962 (Box 152, Folder 2248)
    - Application and Drafts, 1960 (Box 152, Folder 2249)
    - Progress Report, 1962 March (Box 152, Folder 2250)
    - Progress Reports and Drafts, 1962 January-March (Box 153, Folder 2251-2253)
  - NIH:Public Health Service M-3353
    - Application, 1959-1963 (Box 153, Folder 2254)
    - Correspondence, 1959-1963, undated (Box 153, Folder 2255)
    - Correspondence and Financial, 1959-1962 (Box 153, Folder 2256)
    - Application and Draft, 1959 (Box 153, Folder 2257)
    - Notice of Research Project, 1961 (Box 153, Folder 2258)
    - Progress Report, Final and Drafts, 1960 June-1962 May (Box 153, Folder 2259-2261)
    - Interim Progress Report, 1963 April (Box 153, Folder 2262)
    - Progress Reports and Terminal Reports, 1963 August (Box 153, Folder 2263)
    - Supplemental Application, 1960 (Box 153, Folder 2264)
  - NIH:Public Health Service M-01379-01
    - Application, 1963 January (Box 153, Folder 2265)
    - Application and Drafts, 1963 January (Box 153, Folder 2266)
    - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 153, Folder 2267)
    - Application, Draft and Rewrite, 1963 July-September (Box 154, Folder 2268)
    - Notes, 1962, 1963 (Box 154, Folder 2269)
  - NIMH: M-08238
    - Correspondence, 1962-1964 (Box 154, Folder 2270)
    - Correspondence-Personnel, 1963 (Box 154, Folder 2271)
    - Application, 1963 February (Box 154, Folder 2272)
    - Application-Final Draft, 1963 (Box 154, Folder 2273)
    - Application-Preliminary Draft, 1962-1963 (Box 154, Folder 2274)
    - Application-Material on Subphases, Categories, and Rating, 1963 (Box 154, Folder 2275)
  - NIMH: M-08238-01
    - Application, 1963 (Box 154, Folder 2276)
    - Progress Report, 1964 April (Box 154, Folder 2277)
  - NIMH: M-08238-02
    - Correspondence, 1965, 1966 (Box 154, Folder 2278)
    - Application, 1964 March (Box 154, Folder 2279)
  - NIMH: M-08238-03
    - Application, 1965 May (Box 154, Folder 2280)
    - Notice of Research Project, 1966 June (Box 154, Folder 2281)
    - Progress Reports-Final and Rough Draft, 1965 (Box 155, Folder 2282)
    - Progress Report-McDevitt's Draft, 1966 May 18 (Box 155, Folder 2283)
    - Progress Report, 1965 May (Box 155, Folder 2284)
    - Progress Report-Mahler's Draft, 1966 May 19 (Box 155, Folder 2285)
    - Progress Report-Dr. Lapierre's Draft, 1966 May (Box 155, Folder 2286)
  - NIMH: M-08238-04
    - Correspondence-Financial, 1967 (Box 155, Folder 2287)
    - Notice of Research Project, 1967 May (Box 155, Folder 2288)
    - Progress Report, 1966 May (Box 155, Folder 2289)
  - NIMH: M-08238-05
    - Application and Progress Report, 1967 January (Box 155, Folder 2290-2292)
    - Application and Progress Report Notes, 1967 January (Box 155, Folder 2293)
    - Progress Report, Notes, 1967 January (Box 155, Folder 2294-2295)
    - Summary Progress Report, 1967 May (Box 155, Folder 2296)
    - Application, 1967 May (Box 155, Folder 2297)
    - Supplemental Correspondence, 1967, 1968 (Box 155, Folder 2298)
    - Supplemental 2 Application and Notes, 1968 May (Box 156, Folder 2299)
  - Frank Strick Foundation
    - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 156, Folder 2300)
  - The Grant Foundation, Inc.
    - Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 156, Folder 2301)
    - Application, Drafts, and Notes, 1968 (Box 156, Folder 2302)
  - Foundations' Fund for Research in Psychiatry
    - Correspondence, 1969-1974 (Box 156, Folder 2303)
    - Application-Master Copy, Fred Pine Notes, Draft, 1969 July-August (Box 156, Folder 2304-2307)
    - Progress and Final Reports, List of Publications, 1972 June (Box 156, Folder 2308)
  - Foundation for Research in Psychoanalysis
    - Correspondence, 1967-1969 (Box 156, Folder 2309)
    - Application for Research Grant, 1967 (Box 156, Folder 2310)
    - Progress Report, 1968 June (Box 156, Folder 2311)
    - Application for Research Grant-Draft, 1967 (Box 156, Folder 2312)
    - Robert P. Knight V.F.R. Fund of the Foundation for Research in Psychoanalysis
      - Correspondence, 1967-1969 (Box 156, Folder 2313)
      - Application for Research Grant, 1967 (Box 156, Folder 2314)
  - General
    - Department of Health, Education, and Welfare; Public Health Service Correspondence and Publications, 1963-1968, undated (Box 156, Folder 2315)
    - Correspondence, 1968, 1969, 1976 (Box 156, Folder 2316)
    - Application Material, 1967-1969 (Box 156, Folder 2317)
    - Personnel, 1955, 1960-1966 (Box 156, Folder 2318)
- Testing Materials, 1921-1963; Series XI; 2.5 linear feet (5 boxes)
  This series contains standard test materials arranged alphabetically by title of test.
  - Illinois Test of Psycholinguistic Abilities-Experimental Edition
    - Examiner's Manual, 1961 (Box 157, Folder 2319)
    - Picture Book, 1961 (Box 157, Folder 2320)
  - Rorschach, Hermann: Psychodiagnostik
    - Plates, 1921 (Box 157, Folder 2321)
    - Text, 1932 (Box 157, Folder 2322)
    - Plates, 1932 (Box 157, Folder 2323)
    - Text, 1937 (Box 157, Folder 2324)
    - Plates, 1937-1948 (Box 158, Folder 2325-2326)
  - Stanford-Binet Intelligence Scale-Manual, 1960 (Box 158, Folder 2327)
  - Shneidelman, Edwin "Make a Picture Story Test", 1948 (Box 158, Folder 2328)
  - Murray, Henry A. Thematic Apperception Test, 1943 (Box 158, Folder 2329)
  - Wechsler-Bellvue Scale Form I Picture Completion, Block Design Cards, and Arithmetic Problems 9-10, 1946 (Box 158, Folder 2330)
  - Wechsler Intelligence Scale for Children
    - Manual, 1949 (Box 158, Folder 2331)
    - Arithmetic Problems 14-16, Picture Completions and Block Designs, 1963 (Box 159, Folder 2332)
  - Zulliger, Hans
    - "Behn-Rorschach Test"-Plates, 1941 (Box 159, Folder 2333)
    - "Behn-Rorschach Test"-Text, 1941 (Box 159, Folder 2334)
    - "Der Z-Test"-Plates, 1951 (Box 159, Folder 2335)
  - Testing Material: WISC block design: WISC object assembly test-4: WISC picture arrangement, undated (Box 160, Folder 2335)
  - Toys: capgun; doll's dress, shoe, sock; hammer; pencil; piece of chalk; plastic cup; rubber ball; set of figure cards; 2 small box lids; stand; toy vase; wood block, undated (Box 161)
- Videotapes and Film, 1954-1982; Series XII; 10.75 linear feet (16 boxes)
  This series is arranged by type of material and then chronologically within.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
  - Lectures
    - New York Psychoanalytic Institute
      - Lecture 1, Reel 1, 1977; 1; videotape (v-30h) (Box 162)
      - Lecture 1, Reel 2, 1977; 1; videotape (v-30h) (Box 186)